A Guide to the Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA802 FA802
Rockefeller Archive Center
Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
circa 1896-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Cohn, Alfred E. (Alfred Einstein)
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA802
54 Cubic Feet 45 record storage cartons, 1 oversize box.
45 record storage cartons, 1 oversize box.
Biographical/Historical note
Alfred Einstein Cohn, 16 April 1879-20 July 1957.
Physician, humanist, and author. One of first physicians in the United States to make electrocardiograms (Mount Sinai Hospital, New York City, 1910). Clinical researcher at The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, New York City, 1911-1957.
Scope and Contents note
Biographical material, professional and personal correspondence, family letters, board and committee records, manuscripts of scientific and popular writings, notes, photographs, printed materials. Primarily correspondence and writings about heart disease including on aging, arteriosclerosis, digitalis, electrocardiography, hypertension, statistics, World War I cardiac neuroses. Also extensive material on social issues including émigré and refugee physicians and scholars from Europe; medicine in China; Blacks in medicine; graduate and medical education; post-World War II organization of science; psychiatry and psychoanalysis; Alger Hiss case. Correspondents include: Charles A. Beard (1874-1948), Samuel Nathaniel Behrman (1893-1973), Bernard Berenson (1865-1959), Carl Binger (1889-1968), Niels Bohr (1885-1962), Maurice Bowra (1898-1971), Louis D. Brandeis (1856-1941), Alexis Carrel (1873-1944), Harvey Cushing (1869-1939), Arthur W.M. Ellis (1883-1966), John Erskine (1979-1951), Abraham Flexner (1866-1959), Bernard Flexner (1865-1945), Simon Flexner (1863-1946), Felix Frankfurter (1882-1965), Francis Fraser (1885-1964), Herbert Spencer Gasser (1888-1963), Alan Gregg (1890-1957), William Ivins (1881-1961), Henry James (1879-1947), Smith Ely Jelliffe (1866-1945), Lawrence S. Kubie (1896-1973), Karl Landsteiner (1868-1943), Harold Laski (1893-1950), Thomas Lewis (1881-1945), Franklin C. McLean (1888-1968), James Mackenzie (1853-1925), Archibald MacLeish (1892-1982), Henry Alexander Murray, Jr. (1893-), Edward R. Murrow (1908-1975), George Canby Robinson (1878-1960), Charles Singer (1876-1960), Jean Stafford (1915-1979), Mark Van Doren (1894-1972), Hermann Weyl (1885-1955), Paul Dudley White (1886-1973), Alfred N. Whitehead (1861-1947).
Organizational records include: American Society for Clinical Investigation, 1922-1956; Asia Institute, 1940-1952; China Medical Board, 1927-1953; Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced German Scholars, 1933-1944; Institute for Psychoanalysis, 1932-1944; Joint Distribution Committee, 1921-1945; Journal of Clinical Investigation, 1923-1938; New School for Social Research, 1940-1952; Office of Foreign Relief, 1942-1944; Student Service of America, 1941-1948; Sydenham Hospital, 1947-1948; Veterans Bureau, 1924-1947; World's Fair, New York City, 1939.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Alfred E. Cohn.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 C661-U
Conditions Governing Access note
The collection is open for scholarly research.
Medical records are restricted.
Other Finding Aids
FA132 Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Embryology; Physiology; Diseases; Medical sciences; Cardiology; Biology -- Research; Medicine, Preventive; Anatomy; Public health; Medical research; Medical care; Biochemistry; Pathology; Pharmacology; Rockefeller University; Cohn, Alfred E. (Alfred Einstein); Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty, 45 record storage cartons, 1 oversize box.
  - Refugee materials
    - Correspondence and subject files, circa 1934-1946
      - Applications-Wittfogel (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Applications [notebook] Emerg. Comm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Barer, Anna (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
      - Hellendall, Hugo (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Gideonse, Harry D. Student Service (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Duggan, Stephen, Jr. Student Service of America (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Dr. Alfred E. Cohn, Special (MacLeish account) (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - OLD ISS-SSA MATERIAL (Box 1)
        - [Loose papers] (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - Pieces of history and news clippings (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - [Note re folder on property] (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - Memoranda ISS-ISA (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - USSA. ISS. SSA. History (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - Mr. Stephen Duggan (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - Stephen Duggan, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - Duggan, Mr. Laurence (I.I.E.) (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - Campobello. 'My Day' - news-paper clippings, etc. (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - Newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - International Institute for Social Research (Box 1)
        - Horkheimer. Neumann, Pollock (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - "The International Institute of Social Research - Its History, Program and Needs" (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - "The Collapse of German Democracy and the Expansion of National Socialism" (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - R (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - S (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Refugee Economic Corporation (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
      - Prof. Shapley's plan. Cohn. Liebman, Stein (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Seelye, L.H. (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Mr. Fred Stein (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - T (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - U (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - V (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - W (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Wittfogel, [Karl August] (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Minutes, Emergency Committee. Subcommittee on Applications, March-June 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Minutes, Emergency Committee. Subcommittee on Applications, July-November 1943 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Minutes, Emergency Committee. Subcommittee on Applications, January-June 1944 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Minutes, Emergency Committee. Subcommittee on Applications, July 1944-June 1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Whyte, Mr. John I-V (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Whyte, Mr. John I-V (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Whyte, Mr. John I-V (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Whyte, Mr. John I-V (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Kotschnig, Walter M. I-XI (Box 2, Folder 9-19)
      - Duggan, Stephen I-VI, General (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
      - Duggan, Stephen I-VI, National War Fund (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Duggan, Stephen I-VI, Correspondence re. liquidating Emergency Committee (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Duggan, Stephen I-VI, History of Executive Committee (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Duggan, Stephen I-VI, Disposition of Emergency Committee files (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Committee for National Morale, American Committe for Emigre Scholars, Writers, and Artists, Student Service of America
      - Committee for National Morale, A Department of Documentation and Bibliography, 17 February 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Committee for National Morale, Wo (Wohlford, Ke.) (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Committee for National Morale, The Heightening of Morale in the Democracies, 14 December 1940 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Committee for National Morale, Memoranda (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Committee for National Morale, Miscellany (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Guaranty Trust Co. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Friess, Harold L. (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Certificate of Incorporation (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Mead, Nelson P., General (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Mead, Nelson P., Re. Letterheads (Harolow Shapley) (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Mead, Nelson P., Proposed merger with Intl. Rescue Comm. (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Mrs. Staudinger, Dr. and Mrs. Max Ascoli (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Mrs. Staudinger, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Mrs. Staudinger, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Mrs. Staudinger, Fundraising, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Mrs. Staudinger, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Mrs. Staudinger, fundraising, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Staudinger, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Mrs. Staudinger. Resolution, Special fund (Cohn-Mac-Leish book), March 1946 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Loose pages (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Applicants I-X (Box 3, Folder 21-30)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Financial Statements, General (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Financial Statements, S. Stein (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Mrs. Staudinger's COmmittee (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Minutes, Annual, Organizing Executive Committees., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Minutes, Annual, Organizing Executive Committees., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Minutes, Annual, Organizing Executive Committees., 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Committee for National Morale, American Committee for Refugee (Emigre) Scholars, Writers, and Artists - Loose pages re. S.S.A. and I.S.S. (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - International Student Service and Student Service of America - C (James B. Conant), 1941 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - International Student Service and Student Service of America - Dissolution S.S.A., 21 March 1947 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - International Student Service and Student Service of America - D (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - International Student Service and Student Service of America - Old I.S.S. files destroyed (letter re. Joe Neal's report) (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - International Student Service and Student Service of America - Special account (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - American Committee stationary (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Committee for National Morale, Reserved for Mr. Marshall Field I-II (Box 3, Folder 44-46)
  - Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced German Scholars
    Scope and Contents note
    Correspondence, reports, grant applications, memoranda, budgets. Many carbon copies.
    - Murrow, E.R., circa 1933-1936 (Box 4)
      - 1933 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1934 January-May (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 1934 June-August (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 1934 September-December (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Report, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Grant applications, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - 1935 January-March (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - 1935 April-May (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - 1935 June-1936 January (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - re Martin Scheerer, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Drury, Miss Betty, circa 1934-1944 (Box 4)
      - 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - 1937 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - 1938 January-February (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - 1938 March-May (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - 1938 June-December (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - 1939 January-March (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - 1939 April-June (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - 1939 July-December (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - 1940 January-May (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - 1940 June-December (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - 1941 January-June (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - 1941 July-December (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - 1942 January-June (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - 1942 July-December (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - 1943 January-December (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - 1944 January-July (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - 1940 1944 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Duggan, Stephen, circa 1933-1943 (Box 4)
      - 1933-1938 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - 1939 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - 1941 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - 1942 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - 1943 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Refugee materials, circa 1933-1950 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, budgets, reports, photographs
      - Subcommittee on Applications [of the Emergency Committee] (Box 5)
        - Minutes, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - Minutes, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Subcommittee on National Research Associates, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - A (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Aarons, Oscar (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Abrams, Sara (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Adler, Cyrus (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Aub, Joseph C. See also Committee for Medical Emigres Academic Assistance Council (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - B (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Baerwald, Paul (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Beer, Edwin (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Benjamin, Harry (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Besredka, A. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Berle, Adolph (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Berlowitz, Kurt (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Berolzheimer, Edwin M. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Bilheimer, Robert S. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Billikopf, Jacob (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Blumgart, Herrman L. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Brandt, Karl (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Boas, Ernst P. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Bronk, Dr. Detlev W. See under Applications - Lewy, Dr. Fritz (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Brutzkus, J. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Brüning (?) (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Burlingame, C.C. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Bullowa, Alma M. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Bentwich, Norman, circa 1944 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - C (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Cadden, Joseph See under International Student Service of National Student Federation (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Cannon, W.B. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Carrel, Alexis (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Cattell, J. McKeen (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Cook, Walter W.S. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Chamberlain, J.P. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Chesney, Alan M. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Clark, A. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Cobb, Dr. Stanley. See under Boston Committee for Medical Emigres (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Conant, James B. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Coster, Mrs. Charles Henry (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Courant, R. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Curran, Dr. J.A. See under Internships and Residences Greater New York (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Czettel, Ladislas P. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Budget (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - American Joint Distribution Committee, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Stored with OVERSIZE. See oversize register for location. Society for the Protection of Science and Learning. Tentative and Very Incomplete List of Displaced Austrian Scholars and Scientists, 1938 May (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Report of Conference of Country Medical Directors in Europe of the American Joint Distribution Committee and Committee reports, Paris, 1947 May 14-17 (Box 5)
      - Supplement list of Disabled German scholars, 1937-1941 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Reports, Emergency Committee, Academic Assistance Council (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Reports, Emergency Committee, [Two sets], 1934-1942 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - O (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - O'Brian, John Lord. For correspondence re Board of Regents and refugees see under Brandeis, Susan (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - O'Brien, Daniel P. (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Olitsky, P.K. (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Pratt, Mrs. Eliot D. (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - [Institute of International Education. Release, Monday, March 12th [Year? ] 2 pp. re American professors and "the freedom to teach and the freedom to learn" (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - P (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Page, Irvine Pick, E.P. (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Proskauer, Joseph M. See also under Brandeis, Susan (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Putnam, Tracy (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - JOINT DISTRIBUTION COMMITTEE
      See also Emergency Committee file. See also correspondence under World Student Relief file No. 2 [from cross-reference pages in folder].
      - Health Committee, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - [re medical supplies, drugs], circa 1942 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Candidates, circa 1945 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Minutes, Health Committee (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - [Gen. correspondence], circa 1945 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - [Duplicated materials re Hebrew University], circa 1929-1931 (Box 5, Folder 23)
        Stored with OVERSIZE. See oversize register for location.
      - [Nurses Training School, Warsaw, Poland], circa 1924 (Box 5, Folder 24)
        Includes photographs.
      - [re Hadassah Hospitals], 1924 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - [General correspondence], 1923-1927 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - J.D.C. and Hebrew University, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - International Student Service [re electric cooler rental], 1943 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Refugee materials, circa 1935-1939 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Sn (sic) (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Sobeloff, Isidore. See under Welfare Council (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Sobeloff, Edith M. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Bentwich, N. (?) (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Chesney, Alan M. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Chamberlain, J.P. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Cook, Walter W.S. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - [Miscellaneous correspondence. Some pages with plastic clips, apparently these were copied for researcher by R. Sternfeld] (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Biele, Harry D.
      - Thirwall, J.C. Jr.
      - Boas, Ernst P.
      - Blumgart, Herrman
      - Blum, Marie
      - Benjamin, Harry
      - Baerwald, Paul
      - Aub, Joseph C.
    - Duggan, Stephen, circa 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Clark, Mr. Grenville, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Wallach, Sidney, circa 1946-1950 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Writers War Board, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Refugee materials
    Correspondence, agendas, minutes.
    - untitled (Box 6, Folder 1)
      [Bottom of folder labeled: "Budget. Emergency Com." Top of folder labled: "To discuss with Dr. Cohn". Notes, memoranda, analyses].
    - Brandeis, Miss Susan (Box 6, Folder 2)
      [Cross-references on folder: Doskow, Ambrose; F.F. [Felix Frankfurter]; O'Brian, John L., Proskauer, Joe; Warburg, Bettina.].
    - Baehr, Dr. George, circa 1933-1938 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Comité Internat. pour le placement des Intellectuels Refugies [nd] (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Comité des Savants, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Comité des Médecins, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Prof. Bagster-Collins. See also letters attached to covering letters from Mr. E.R. Murrow, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Dr. Cohn's memoranda for the High Commission (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Dr. A.E. Cohn [Memoranda], 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Agendas [Emergency Comm.], 1933-1936 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Agendas, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Agendas, 1939 January-July (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Agendas, 1930 September-November (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Agendas, 1940 January-May (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Agendas, 1940 June-December (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Agendas. Subcommittee on Applications, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Agendas, Subcommittee on Applications, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Agendas, Executive Comm., 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Minutes [Emergency Committee], 1933-1935 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Minutes, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Minutes, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Minutes Feb-May, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Minutes, 1939 September-November (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Emergency Committee — Sub-Committee Placements, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Minutes (Executive Committee) (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Executive Committee 1941- [Minutes, 1941-44] (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Boston Committee on Medical Emigrés - Aub, Joseph C., 1938 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Boston Committee on Medical Emigrés - Cobb, Dr. Stanley, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Boston Committee on Medical Emigrés - Miscellaneous (Mrs. William Herman), 1941 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Boston Committee on Medical Emigrés - Loose papers, some with plastic clips, apparently for photocopying (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Boston Committee on Medical Emigrés - Fine, Dr. Jacob (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Boston Committee on Medical Emigrés - Biele, Harry D. Emergency Committee for Displaced Foreign Medical Scientists. Thurwall, J.C. Segal, Lucille. See also under National Committee for Resettlement of Foreign Physicians, National Refugee Service. Segal, Lucille. In 1945--See under National Committee Resettlement of Fn. Physn. File #7 (1940-1944). (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Student Service of America (SSA), Inc., circa 1941-1948
    International Student Service (ISS) Correspondence, minutes, accounts, reports, memoranda, pamphlets, clippings.
    - [SSA letters, re loan payments], circa 1945-1947 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - [Letters and checks], circa 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - [Check book], 1946-1948 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Account book, SSA (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Discharge of ISS debt (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - ["Special meeting of the Student Service of America held at Hunter College, Friday, "], 1947 March 21 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - [Pages from spiral notebook: SSA accounts] (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Joseph P. Lash, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - ISS - Last Meeting, 1943 January 27 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Mt. Holyoke debt. Boardman Bump, Eliot Pratt, circa 1943-1945 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - SSA letterbook (Box 7, Folder 11)
      Contains minutes, memoranda, letters, pamphlets.
    - [Drafts and clipping of AEC article published in The New Leader, 8 August 1942. Part of series accompanying George N. Shuster essay, "Education in War Time"] (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - A-B (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Abernethy, Bradford S. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - American Airlines (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Auerbach, L.P. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Ballou, Richard (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Blake, Miss (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Bolte, Charles G. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - C (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Malcolm W. Davis) (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Cheek, Mary Ashby (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Clarke, James H. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Committees, Nominations to (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Cohn, A.E. Worksheets, etc.; Memos (Box 7, Folder 15)